So the answer is the first three are all good reasons
因此 答案是前三个都是很好的原因
to focus on how time scales with input size, rather than absolute
关于为什么专注于时间长度与输入的规模 而不是
time. So the first reason is if we have an understanding of
绝对时间 因此第一个原因是 如果我们了解
how the time depends on input size, well then, we can predict
根据输入大小的时间消耗 那么我们可以
how long it will take before we actually execute a program. If
在实际执行程序之前预测需要多长时间
we have to run the program to figure out how long it
如果我们必须运行程序来确定需要多长时间
takes, well that's not going to be very useful because we have actually
那就没什么用了 因为我们其实已经
finished it. We have got the result we want. If we only
做完了 我们已经得到了我们想要的结果 如果我们只
learn how long it takes on that particular input, we
知道这个特定输入需要多长时间 我们
haven't learned anything useful to figure out, what it will
得不到什么有用的信息
cost to run it on some other input. So we
关于在其他输入上运行 它需要花费的时间 所以我们
want to be able to make predictions, by understanding how the running
希望能够作出预测 通过了解运行时间如何
time depends on the actual size of the input. The
依赖于输入的实际大小
second reason is also true. By understanding how time scales with
第二个原因也是如此 通过了解时间与
input size, we get a better idea of how the
输入大小的关系 我们可以更好地了解
cost will change over time. Computers keep getting cheaper and faster.
成本随时间的变化 计算机会越来越便宜 速度会越来越快
>> This was observed by Gordon Moore in 1965.
— 戈登·摩尔 (Gordon Moore) 在1965年观察到这一点
And turned into the notion that we sometimes call Moore's Law
现在我们有时称之为摩尔定律的概念
today. It's not a law in the sense of a physical
这不是物理规律意义上的定律
law, but it's a law in the sense that the history
但它是一个定律 计算机历史
of computing has followed this trend, where the amount of computing
一直遵循这一趋势 其中 以相同的成本
power you get for the same cost, approximately doubles every 18
获得的计算能力大约每18个月增加一倍
months. So what you can get for $1,000 today is half
1,000美元在今天可以获得的是
what you'll be able to get for $1,000 a year and
在一年半后可以获得的一半
a half from now. That's a pretty nice property to have,
这是一个相当不错的特性
but it means that understanding the cost of something today
但它意味着 了解今天的成本
doesn't tell us very much. What we really want to understand
并没有告诉我们什么 我们真正想了解的是
is the cost in a more fundamental way. The third
更根本的成本 第三个
reason is also true. That by understanding how time scales with
原因也是对的 通过了解时间
input size, we get a much better fundamental understanding of
与输入大小的关系 我们得到对算法更好更根本的
our algorithms, than if we just had some absolute time measurements
了解 比起我们只对几个不同的输入
for a few different inputs. The fourth answer is not
绝对时间的测量 第四个答案是
correct. Abstract answers can be just as wrong as concrete answers.
不正确的 抽象答案可能与具体答案一样错误
But having good abstract answers will allow us to understand
但是 拥有好的抽象答案将使我们了解
things much more deeply, than a few specific concrete answers will.
事情变得更深入 比起几个特定的具体答案